GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
I'm arresting you for the murder
of the boy you blew up
under the Crown Point Bridge.
You blew that kid sky-high.
You are lying! You
are a lying traitor!
I need you at the
head of the GCPD.
Let them think you're a hero.
GORDON: I screwed up, Harv.
Sofia hired the Pyg.
And I covered it up.
SOFIA: We all have
to make sacrifices.
Thought i was all about family.
Never said it was
a happy family.
(SCREAMING)
My friend thinks
we're here to rob you.
But I know you torture plants
- in the name of science, Roland Charles.
- (GRUNTS)
Lee Thompkins may have made
Ed strong, but I see the other you.
- The Riddler.
- (NYGMA LAUGHING)
I'm back.
(LAUGHING)
(MAN COUGHS)
(MAN CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(MAN LAUGHING BOISTEROUSLY)
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
(MAN COUGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
(MAN CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(GAS HISSING)
(SNIFFING)
What's that smell?
(MISSILE WHISTLING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
(ALARMS SOUNDING)
Uncle Penguin
sent me to get you.
Come on, let's get ice cream.
(BLOWS LANDING)
The Narrows is under
new management.
(GRUNTING)
- The Narrows is Sampson's turf.
- (WHIMPERING)
And Sampson... Well,
collects protection.
And people need to
find out what happens
when you don't pay!
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH WHIMPERING)
(GUN COCKS)
Please. My family.
Do I look like an animal to you?
I wouldn't hurt your family.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Unless they don't pay me!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
GORDON: Before Don Falcone died,
he warned me, I had no idea
what I'd brought to the city.
I now know he was
talking about the Pyg.
Somebody must've told him.
My guess, that person has evidence
that links Sofia to the Pyg's murders.
Why not come forward
with what you know?
It has to be more than
just my word against hers.
Or are you afraid the truth is
going to drag you down, too?
- Oh, Harvey, we've been over this.
- When did you know?
I swear, I had no idea
until after it was too late.
Now, you can be pissed, but
this is bigger than both of us.
I need to know I
can count on you.
Yeah, Jim.
I'll help you take down Sofia.
But then you're gonna have
to pay for what you've done.
I personally guarantee it.
I know an ex-Falcone assassin.
Might have beans to spill.
Went by the name "the
Scandinavian Skinner."
Sit tight. I have
history with the Skinner.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
SELINA: You know, you
have, like, no food in here, right?
BRUCE: Selina?
What are you doing here?
What's... What's wrong?
SELINA: Why does something
have to be wrong for me to come by?
Seriously?
I need help. (SIGHS)
You mean money.
(SIGHS) I stole something,
fenced it, now I want to get it back.
And I'd steal it, but
the fence is difficult.
So, I need money.
Why don't you just ask
Barbara Kean for the money?
'Cause I don't wanna
get her involved.
Look, I'll pay you back.
I just don't have time because
if the fence sells what I...
But you still haven't told me
why you wanna get it back.
Because it's what I stole
from Roland Charles.
- The Wayne scientist...
- That Ivy killed.
(SELINA SIGHS)
I didn't know she was
gonna do that, Bruce.
(STUTTERS) And I just...
You feel bad.
Look, if you don't wanna help
me, then I'll just find another way.
Let me get some cash.
There's oatmeal raisin
cookies in the blue tin.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
Why are you dragging me here?
(BARKS)
Cobblepot.
A guy called. Wanted
me to give you a message.
Finally! (EXHALES)
"I can lend you a hand,
but you won't find me helpful.
"My name may sound tasty,
but the flavor is dreadful."
Is it "knuckle sandwich"?
- (CHUCKLES) Yeah.
- No.
- (MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
- (KIDS GIGGLING)
Hello, Agnes.
Or should I say, "the Skinner"?
Detective Bullock.
I don't go by that name anymore.
I'm retired.
- You kids, don't spoil your dinner.
- Okay, Grandma.
I'm looking for someone
who might've been Don Falcone's
eyes and ears when he was down south.
Why would I tell you that?
Because we have history.
That history got me
four years in the gulag.
Either you help me,
or I tell your beautiful
grandchildren
how their meemaw
used to skin people alive.
Hey, kids, you wanna
hear a really funny story?
All right. No, it's all right.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
HARVEY: Never mind.
Falcone only really
trusted the bookkeeper.
The one who always
smelled of fish.
- Mr. Penn?
- Yeah.
Penn.
And good luck finding
him. I heard he vanished.
Poof.
(GRUNTS ANGRILY)
How is Martin gone?
(PANTS)
Never mind.
Penguin is coming.
Go to Arkham and kill him now.
Okey-dokey.
- Oh, by the way...
- (DOOR OPENS)
a buddy of mine just
got out of the hospital.
He's looking for work.
You mind if he tags along?
Hiya.
Just make sure Penguin
dies choking on his own blood.
HARVEY: Why is
Cobblepot in the infirmary?
Heard he mouthed off to a guard,
then slipped and hit his head.
(GASPS)
Bullock. This is a surprise.
Hey, Oswald. Good
to see you, too.
I just had a few questions
about a former employee of yours.
- (WOMAN SCREAMING)
- (GASPS)
WOMAN: They got guns!
Open that door!
(PANICKED CHATTERING)
GUARD: Everybody, split up.
HARVEY: Get out
of the way. Clear out!
Move, move, move!
Hey!
You two, don't come any closer.
ZSASZ: Bullock?
Dude, I thought you
stopped being a cop.
Guess it didn't take, huh?
Not so much.
- You remember Wendell, don't you?
- Howdy.
I don't know why you two
are here, and I don't care.
Walk away!
See, I'm afraid
we can't do that.
(WEAPON WHIRRING)
We're not leaving here
without the Penguin.
ZSASZ: Harvey.
Do yourself a favor,
give us Penguin, and live to
get drunk another day. Hmm?
As tempting as that sounds, no.
- (BELL RINGING)
- (ALARM BLARING)
GUARD 1: Come
on, let's go. Let's go.
(GUARDS CLAMORING)
It's okay.
We'll come back.
GUARD 2: He's escaped.
Oswald Cobblepot has escaped.
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(PANICKED CHATTERING
AND SCREAMING)
- (WHIMPERING)
- (GUNSHOTS)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Nygma.
BRUCE: What?
You're just different.
Different how?
You were a complete
douchebag to me at the club.
And now you're not.
Listen, Selina,
about that night...
Oh, no, you're not going to
try to apologize to me, are you?
No, I just wanted to say...
Save it.
Because you are probably going to
be a douchebag to me later anyway.
Missed you, too.
Kitty Cat, back so soon?
'Sup, Floyd?
I'm gonna need that stuff I
brought to you the other day.
FLOYD: Oh.
You mean this stuff?
The stuff you tried to
break in and steal last night?
You think I wouldn't
check the camera?
Great.
You remember what I said
about being a douchebag?
I'll pay double
what you gave me.
This your bank?
How about I take the money
and I keep your stuff?
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
Next time...
- (GRUNTS)
- take the deal.
(GRUNTS) Got it.
I knew that as soon as I rescued
Martin that she'd send her hitmen.
How is Martin?
Snug as a bug in a rug.
Here, will you hold this?
So, do you wanna
know how I found him?
So it turns out, Zsasz,
huge fan of the disco.
- So I dress up as an old Polish...
- Perhaps another time!
Now that Martin is safe, we
need to focus on killing Sofia.
We need a power base.
I know. That's why we're here.
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
Hello. (CHUCKLES)
Ed. You're back.
- Mmm-hmm.
- How are you doing?
Worlds better.
Honestly, thank you.
Oh, no. What
happened to your hand?
Sofia Falcone.
Smashed it with a hammer, and
then threw me out on the street.
And put Sampson in
charge of The Narrows.
I see.
But together, we can
get that bitch back.
Show her that she can't just
take everything we've built.
Yeah, Oswald, she can't help.
LEE: What is this?
What is going on?
What's wrong with you?
I let him out of his cage, and he,
in turn, helped me get out of mine.
You're him.
The Riddler.
(CHUCKLES)
Hi, Lee.
You know, I was really hoping that
you were still running The Narrows,
maybe could help us, but...
Guess not.
Yeah, so what's your
next brilliant idea?
Sofia will have turned Falcone
Mansion into a stronghold.
It will be impossible
to get at her.
Oswald, you think I
don't have a backup plan?
I'm gonna have Victor
Fries put you in a block of ice.
I'm gonna take you to Sofia
like a chilly Trojan horse,
- pretend to hand you over...
- (CHUCKLES)
Are you kidding me?
It's a fantastic plan.
Try again!
All right, let me help.
Look, all of your capos have
pledged their loyalty to Sofia...
Do you think I can't handle it?
I know you can't.
Look what she did to me.
I will pull the trigger
on that bitch myself.
That's some tough tongue,
but we both know that's just talk.
Enough! Both of you.
If we wanna fight
Sofia, we need muscle.
I agree.
I can tell you where to look.
Don't you think he misses you?
Who... Who is she talking about?
NYGMA: Grundy!
You down here, big fella?
Your best friend and pal,
Edward Nygma.
Hey, guess what?
I'm smart again!
(WATER LAPPING)
There he is.
Pale skin, nobody upstairs...
Who's my buddy?
Correct. You.
Oh, boy.
So, we're corralling allies.
Penguin and I are going
to kill Sofia Falcone.
And we need a big galoot like you for
cannon fodder. How does that sound?
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
What's your problem? Why
are you looking at me like that?
- (GASPS)
- (GRUNTS)
Oh, dear.
You're not the only
one who got smart.
Okay, Butch, I helped you.
You remember?
Hot, hot arm.
Yeah, Ed put out fire.
But you're not Ed anymore.
(GRUNTS)
And I'm not Grundy.
PENGUIN: Where the hell is Ed?
LEE: He'll be here.
No. No, he's betrayed me, too.
I know it. I never
should have trusted him!
Calm down.
No, do not tell me to calm down.
You have no idea
what I've been through!
Calm down! Ed will be here.
He will bring Grundy, and
we will make Sofia pay.
I can't wait any longer.
HARVEY: How did Nygma get
in touch with Penguin anyway?
GORDON: I don't know.
Nothing's ever
easy with you, is it?
It's always like, "Find Lee,
and then she'll point us to Ed.
"And then we'll find Penguin,
"and he'll tell us
where to find Penn."
Or we could just talk
to Oswald right now.
What?
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- MAN: Hey, you son of a...
(PENGUIN GRUNTING)
What are you doing here?
We're looking for an Arkham escapee
about yea tall, walks with a limp,
mommy complex?
Those trumped-up charges
you used to put me away
have lost their teeth.
- Martin is still alive.
- So produce him.
PENGUIN: Nope. He is not safe
until Sofia Falcone has
been dealt with permanently.
I think you and I want
the same thing, Oswald.
We both want Sofia to go away.
Then turn around and walk away.
Let me do what I do.
No. I want her in jail, and
for that I need evidence.
I want your
bookkeeper, Mr. Penn.
What would he know about...
That little weasel
was working for her!
Yeah, he was working for her,
for Don Falcone, everybody!
You might want to check
your management style, pal.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
I'm gonna kill him.
Oswald. Oswald.
Calm down.
You show us where
we can find Mr. Penn,
and I'll let you walk away.
I don't believe you.
HARVEY: Sofia sent
Zsasz to Arkham to kill you.
Her goons run The Narrows.
How long do you think it's
gonna take till she finds you?
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(SIGHS)
I overheard Mr. Penn talk about a place
just out of town, near the tri-corner.
The Spa Bosh Sumka.
Offers special therapy.
If he's hiding, he's
probably there.
Oswald.
Thank you.
That's really nice. Now, put
your hands behind your back.
No. No! No, we had a deal!
Harvey, what are you doing?
If you want to look
the other way, Jim, fine.
I didn't agree to
squat. Come on.
PENGUIN: (SOBS) No! No!
- I will not forget this!
- Relax.
If your information
on Penn is good,
at least you'll be
free of Sofia Falcone.
ZSASZ: Well, well, well.
Sofia's gonna be very curious to
know why you're looking for Penn.
Hey, Penguin. Remember me?
Oh, God, no.
Wait, is Penn
important or something?
That's a yes. You see
that? That's his "yes" face.
Get him in the car.
Guess I'll have to
go dig him up myself.
Now, you boys
want to come quietly,
or do you want to
do it the fun way?
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- The fun way. Nice.
- (GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
(WHIMPERING)
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
- Lee.
- Shut up and get down.
(ENGINE STARTS)
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- Lee?
Come on. Let's get out of here.
We need to get to
Penn before Zsasz does.
We need a car.
(SIGHS)
Migraine still?
It's like I've been hit
in the head with a brick.
- (MUFFLED GRUNTING)
- What is that stink?
(MUFFLED, INDISTINCT SPEAKING)
Should've known.
Grundy smell like old dentures.
TABITHA: It's him.
I know. I can smell him.
- (BARBARA SNIFFING)
- Hey there, Barbara.
(GASPS)
Scary.
Nygma tried to recruit
me against Sofia.
He's working for Penguin.
(LAUGHS)
I figured after all Ed did to you,
you should be the one to kill him.
Wait, Butch.
Don't just walk away again.
Tabby, I'm gonna find a
way to get back to the old me.
I promise.
(MUFFLED SPEAKING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
- (HIGH PITCHED RINGING)
- (GROANS)
- (MUFFLED, DISTORTED VOICE SPEAKING)
- (BARBARA WHIMPERING SOFTLY)
TABITHA: (ECHOES) Any ideas?
(GASPING)
You okay?
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
I'm fine.
We send Nygma back to Sofia.
She will torture him
to get to Penguin.
Lee has no more allies.
Boom, rebellion
quells, we're heroes.
Then what about Nygma?
He just gets to walk away?
(MUFFLED SPEAKING)
When Sofia doesn't need
him anymore, she'll kill him.
(SIGHS)
Same end result,
none of the headache.
Well, we did find Penguin,
but then he got away.
So why aren't you looking for
him, instead of wasting my time?
Because I also found out that
Gordon is looking for Mr. Penn.
Find Penn before Gordon does.
Yeah, so, Penn, Penguin... I
mean, where are we priorities-wise?
Do both.
Thank you for
coming to my rescue.
Don't bother. Without
you, I can't get to Sofia.
Touching.
- I cannot believe I'm doing this.
- Believe it.
No Ed, no Grundy.
We're running out of time.
You know this cockamamie
scheme will probably get me killed?
If it puts Sofia in the
ground, I'm okay with that.
(GUN COCKING)
VICTOR: The last
time you came in here
with one of your
schemes to regain the city,
you promised every resource I
needed to reverse my condition.
So, that didn't happen.
An omission I regret, and
will rectify if given the chance.
Uh-huh.
- (GAS HISSING)
- (PENGUIN YELPING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS)
You cannot honestly tell
me you are happy here.
Tinkering away,
on whatever these...
Don't touch that.
You need money for your
research, Sofia wants Penguin.
So you deliver him to her,
you can name your price.
VICTOR: I may have something.
Keep this on you. It's on a timer.
Best I can do on short notice.
If being frozen affects my
brain the way it did Nygma,
- I cannot afford...
- Ready?
- Not yet! I...
- Don't care.
(METAL MUSIC PLAYING)
So now you're
going to return it?
- Selina, you said...
- Can you do it?
That's really why
you came to me.
It wasn't about the money.
You did not kill Roland Charles.
I was there, though.
And what am I
supposed to say, I...
"I stole your jewelry. Sorry."
Sometimes that's enough.
- (DRILL WHIRRING)
- (NYGMA SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS IN PAIN)
His strength of
mind is impressive.
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
You are going to tell me
where to find Penguin,
or I will make all of this
look like a pleasant dream.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, okay.
I can be done with the teeth,
the eyes or the mind. What am I?
I can be humorous, but
I'm never funny! (LAUGHS)
What am I?
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
Tell me where he is.
I am telling you! (LAUGHING)
You're just too
stupid to figure it out!
(SCREAMING)
- Miss Falcone, you've got a visitor.
- Kind of in the middle of something.
Guy's got Penguin.
(NYGMA GROANS)
Bring him in.
(SOFIA SCOFFS)
(GASPS, CHUCKLES)
Well, this is unexpected.
Heard you were
looking for Penguin.
He never was a great boss.
Well, well, Oswald.
Is he alive in there?
VICTOR: Maybe.
I want $100,000.
Pay him.
ZSASZ: I'm not even gonna ask.
Oh, by the way, I
found out where Penn is.
(GASPS)
Take him to the docks, shoot
him, and throw him in the river.
(GRUNTS)
Watch Penguin.
Let's go get Mr. Penn.
(KNOCKS)
MAN: Lovely, Miss
Gonzalez, well done.
Pull a little harder. Right.
That's it, Miss McGee. Come on.
(LIVELY CHATTER AND LAUGHTER)
What fresh level
of hell is this?
WOMAN: Who is hungry?
(PEOPLE MIMICKING BABY NOISE)
GCPD!
We're looking for Arthur Penn.
What are you doing?
Anonymity is a strict
edict here at the resort.
I bet.
- HARVEY: That's him.
- Penn. Penn!
Oh, no.
Let's take a walk.
As you were.
(PEOPLE GIGGLING AND BABBLING)
(ICE CRACKING)
(MUFFLED BEEPING)
- Mr. Cobblepot.
- (SHIVERING)
You are working for
her, too! (CHUCKLING)
- I assure you...
- Of course you are!
Where is she?
- You don't understand.
- (YELLS) Where is she?
- (YELLS)
- (THE DENTIST GRUNTS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Is it done?
- Sofia left before I could kill her.
She's on her way to stop Gordon.
Meet me at the Spa Bosh
Sumka, and we will kill her together.
(GASPS)
Nygma was here?
Miss Falcone tried to
get him to turn on you.
What?
He endured a
tremendous amount of pain.
He wouldn't give you up.
Where is he now?
Her thugs took him
to the docks to kill him.
(GRUNTS)
I have worked for Don Falcone
for years, before Mr. Cobblepot.
When Sofia came to Gotham,
Don Falcone asked me to
keep an eye on his daughter.
She found out.
So you made another deal with
her, you weaselly, triple agent, you.
It's how you stay
alive in this business.
And she let me live.
As long as I informed to
her about Mr. Cobblepot.
That's how she was able to
stay one step ahead of Penguin,
with inside information.
Then what?
She asked me to put her in
touch with Lazlo Valentine.
The Pyg.
So I did.
But I told Don
Falcone right away.
All right, you're
coming with us.
We need your
statement for the record.
Get down!
- (PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- (GORDON GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
Get Penn out of here.
He's all that matters.
We've got to get
you to the hospital.
Gunshot would draw attention.
The cops will be here soon.
I can make it till they arrive.
SOFIA: James Gordon.
We could've had a
good thing, you and I.
You just had to go and ruin it.
Go.
That's an order.
Get Penn.
Get Gordon.
- (ALL EXCLAIMING)
- Get out!
(GRUNTS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GUNSHOT)
(GRUNTS)
(GUN CLICKS)
- (SHELLS CLATTER)
- (GRUNTING)
- (TIRES SCREECH)
- HARVEY: Lee!
- Where's Sofia?
- In there with Jim.
- Take the car.
- He's hurt bad.
Get in.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
Can't catch a break today.
Let's go get a milkshake.
(GRUNTING)
SOFIA: Jim, you really
are such a disappointment.
(GRUNTS)
Would it have been so bad,
being in the palm of my hands,
having me chip away
at your soul little by little?
Was it so important to
rob me of my revenge?
GORDON: That hurt.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
It wasn't about me.
I wasn't going to
give you the GCPD.
Of course, it was about you.
Your pride, your arrogance.
Do you think that
what I was asking for
was any different than what
my father had for 30 years?
You mean your
father who you killed?
Yes.
I killed him,
because he disappointed me.
Just like you.
You know, Jim, oddly
enough, I still care for you.
Beg me for your life.
Ask for forgiveness.
And we can start over.
Sofia...
Go to hell.
SOFIA: James Gordon,
this is where our story ends.
(GUNSHOT)
- You.
- Yeah.
Me.
Stay with me, Jim.
(ECHOES) Jim, can you hear me?
(NYGMA LAUGHING)
MAN: Come on, now. Come on.
Hey, I've got a riddle for you.
What's got a bullet in its head
and sinks to the bottom of the river?
- You.
- (BOTH LAUGH MANIACALLY)
The real torture
is that those idiotic horns
will be the last I ever hear.
Just do it!
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (BOTH GRUNT)
Oswald.
How?
Did you already kill Sofia?
No. She left the mansion
to pursue Jim Gordon.
Why didn't you just
stay at the home,
wait till she came
there and killed her?
Then I wouldn't have
been here on time.
You gave up your revenge for me?
Trust is so very hard
to find in Gotham.
But I trust you, Ed.
I have a strong desire
to never ever
see this pier again.
(EXHALES) I agree.
(MONITOR BEEPING STEADILY)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Hey.
Surprised you're alive?
(GORDON GRUNTS)
Yeah.
- How?
- How do you think?
Lee.
She kept you alive till
the medics got there.
Even one-handed,
she's a damn good doctor.
- Sofia?
- In a coma.
Amazing she's not dead.
Harvey.
When I get out of here,
I'm going to confess.
My connection to Sofia,
my role with the Pyg. All of it.
I gotta come clean.
No.
What do you mean?
Who would benefit
from that? You.
You get to be the martyr,
feel better about yourself.
The GCPD loses its hero. No!
You want to pay your debt?
You live with it.
Just like I do.
So, Sofia wins after all?
It's what the city needs.
Where's Lee?
She went back to The Narrows.
Said she had
unfinished business.
- (ALL CHEERING)
- (BLOWS LANDING)
- MAN 1: Not so tough now.
- Get him!
- Yes! Come on!
- MAN 2: You got him!
(GRUNTING)
SAMPSON: All right.
I'll go. I'll go.
Oh, I know you'll go.
Just not yet.
Hold his hand.
No. No!
No!
What are you doing? No! No!
(GRUNTS) No!
- (GRUNTS)
- (YELLING IN PAIN)
- (LEE GRUNTS)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
Stop! Don't!
- (GRUNTING)
- (SAMPSON YELLING IN PAIN)
("FIRE" PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED) With Sofia gone,
Penguin's gonna try and take control
of Gotham again,
maybe even try and kill us.
Could you just give me a second?
Barbara, we have to act.
- We can't just stand around...
- (SHOUTS) I said shut up!
(GASPING)
(SONG CONTINUES PLAYING)